Oh, man! ls that what l think it is?
天，那是我想的东西吗？
All right, cheesedicks. Welcome to the Nam. Follow me.
好了，新丁 欢迎来到越南，跟我来
l'll be dipped in shit. New meat!
糟了，有新血
You dudes gonna love the Nam. For-fucking-ever.
你们会很喜欢越南的，永远的
365 and a wake-up. Oh, lord.
365天
Watch it below!
下面小心
Morehouse, drop back to slack.
莫浩，走快点
Who's on tail-end Charlie?
查理，谁在队尾？
Eagle, Eagle, Ripper Six, Pos rep follows,'
总部，这是六队 位置如下…
Lemur, Alpha, Whiskey, Alpha, Foxtrot...,
L、A、W、A、F…
Warren, you get out on flank.
华伦，你去队侧
-Hey, Hoffmeister! -Yo?
-何迈特 -什么事？
You got a smoke?
你有香烟吗？
-No, man, l don't. -Sin loi, man.
-没有 -没关系
Bravo 2-6. What's the delay on point?
B26，为何延迟了？
Having compass trouble again?
又找不到路了吗？
Get a move on, boy.
继续走
Boy, what you waiting for?
你还在等什么？
He ain't gonna bite you.
他不会咬你
That's a good gook. Good and dead.
那是越南兵，死了
-Cherry. -Yo, cherry!
-新丁 -新丁
Move it out. Six says we're jamming them up back there. Over.
行动，第六队说我们挡住了他们 完毕
Tell that dipshit to get fucked.
叫他去见鬼吧
This is 2-5. Be advised. We're moving out shortly. Out.
这是第25队，听好 我们很快便出发，完毕
What's the matter with you, Taylor?
戴，你怎么了？
You are one simple son of a bitch.
你是个大混蛋
l'm sorry, sergeant.
中士，对不起
Get that other cherry up here. Gardner. And the doc.
叫另外那个新丁过来，葛拿 还有军医
Gardner, doc, up!
葛拿，军医，上前来
Gardner, get your ass up the hill, you fat fuck!
葛拿，快过来，你他妈的
Hurry up, bubble-butt!
大胖子，快点
-You all right? -Ants.
-你有没有事？ -蚂蚁
l got ants all over my neck.
我脖子全都是蚂蚁
You got some red ants.
这些是红蚂蚁
Reds are killers. Black ants are the worse.
红蚂蚁是杀手 黑蚂蚁最可怕
Hurry up, lard-ass!
快点，混球
l'm so tired!
我很累
Just a little.
只喝一点
Don't drink too much. l don't want you drinking any more.
不要喝太多 你不要再喝了
l don't want you cramping up.
我不想你抽搐
You're humping too much stuff.
你带着太多东西
You don't need half this shit.
有一半是不需要的
l'll haul it for you.
我帮你拿
But next time check with me first, all right?
但请你下次先向我请示
Thanks, sarge.
谢谢你，中士
-Are you okay? -Yeah.
-你有没有事？ -没事
2-2, this is six, I understand you have a bird inbound at your pos,
这是总部，有直升机接近你们
Bravo Six, be advised.
总部，请留意
Resupply helo is inbound at this time, Over,
军资直升机正驶来
Go, you people! Get that ammo off now!
快点搬军火下来
lt ain't D-E-R-E. lt's D-E-A-R.
这个字不是这样写的
And Sarah ain't got no two R's, King. Damn, you dumb!
而且莎拉也不是那样写的 笨蛋
Don't matter. She know what l mean.
没关系，她会明白我的意思
She don't read too good nohow.
她也不大认识字
Look at this shit! Pork again!
你看，又是猪肉
Trade me that turkey loaf for this pork shit, man. l can't eat this shit.
我跟你换你的火鸡 我不能再吃这玩意了
What you been smoking?
你抽了什么？
l hope you don't get that laundry gig. Your ass need to hump, hump.
希望你不用洗衣服 你要运动一下
Hey, white boy! What you waiting for?
白小子，你在等什么？
That hole won't dig itself.
那个洞不会自己出现的
Come on. Get your dick skin on that thing!
快点掘
You ain't got all day! Dig, dig!
时间无多，快点掘…
Somebody once wrote, ''Hell is the impossibility of reason, ''
有人写过 “地狱是不可理喻的”
That's what this place feels like,' hell,
这个地方就像地狱
I hate it already, and it's only been a week,
我只是来了一周但已经讨厌这里
Some goddamn week, Grandma,
祖母，这一周很痛苦
The hardest thing I've ever done is go on point three times this week,
最辛苦的事就是这星期站岗三次
I don't know what I'm doing,
我不知道我在做什么
A gook could be right in front of me and I wouldn't know it,
我连越共在我面前出现也不知道
I'm so tired,
我实在很累
We get up at 5,'00 a,m...
我们早上五点起床…
...hump all day, camp around 4 or 5, dig a foxhole, eat...
整天走动，四、五点钟扎营 掘壕沟，进食…
...then put out an all-night ambush or a listening post,
然后整晚埋伏，或是当哨兵
Nobody tells me how to do anything because I'm new,
我是新来的，没有人教我任何事
Nobody cares about the new guys, They don't want to know your name,
没人理会新丁 他们连你的名字也不想知道
A new guy's life isn't worth much because he hasn't put his time in yet,
新丁的生命不重要因他没有经验
If you're gonna get killed in Nam, it's better to get it in the first weeks,
若在越南战死，最好在最初几周
The logic being, you don't suffer that much,
原因是你不会受太多苦
If you're lucky, you stay in the perimeter...
如果幸运，留在外围防线…
...then pull a guard shift, so you sleep three or four hours,
守卫时能够睡三至四小时
But you don't really sleep,
但你不能真的入睡
I don't think I can keep this up for a year,
我认为我撑不到一年
I've made a big mistake coming here,
我不应该来这里
We got beaucoup movement.
我们有很多活动
3rd Battalion got hit 1 5 klicks north of here.
第三部队在15公里外被袭击
Charlie had claymores strung in the trees.
越共在树上挂上地雷
Blew a whole fucking platoon to pieces. Bad shit.
整排军队被炸，真倒霉
Got two lieutenants and a captain.
两个中尉和一个上尉被炸死
Jesus.
我的天
All right, who do you want on ambush?
你想谁去埋伏？
Elias, you take your squad out.
奕礼，你带你的小队出去
Warren, stay in, but l need Tex and Junior from your squad.
华伦，留下 我需要德斯和小尊
Roger.
知道
Move out in 2-0 mikes.
调动到20M的位置
l thought it was O'Neill's turn tonight.
我以为今晚轮到奥尼
Tubbs and Morehouse are short.
托斯和莫浩经验不足
Fu Sheng is going on R and R tomorrow. You want to send them out on ambush?
福生明天放假，还要他们去吗？
You got the fresh meat, buddy.
你要带新丁去
They don't know shit and we'll probably run into something. Think about it.
他们什么都不懂 可能会遇到事情，仔细想想
Great. What do you want me to do?
太好了，你想我怎样做？
Get one of my guys zapped so a lame ass can get his beauty sleep?
你想我为了一个混蛋要好好睡觉 而让手下被杀吗？
Hey, O'Neill...
奥尼…
...take a break.
别再罗嗦
You needn't be a prick every day.
你不用每天都这么讨厌
Elias, get your men ready.
奕礼，叫手下准备好
Guy's in 3 years, thinks he's Jesus Christ.
他来了三年，以为自己是耶稣
O'Neill, your short-timers stay in, but you go out.
奥尼，他们留下，但你要去
l need veterans out there.
我需要有经验的老兵
Sergeant Barnes?
彭斯中士？
l think in front of the men, l need to give the orders.
在他们面前应由我下命令
Yes, sir.
是，长官
Shit, looks like rain.
看来会下两
lt's gonna piss on us all night.
我们整晚都要在两中了
lt'll put a serious case of crotch rot on that ugly face of yours.
会令你脸烂掉
Goddamn, man. You break your ass for the white man.
你为那个白人而冒险
No justice around here.
这里是没有公义的
What's O'Neill got, a nose up the lieutenant's ass already?
奥尼又触怒中尉了？
Why do we always get fucking ambush?
为什么总是我们负责埋伏？
Because it's politics, man. Politics.
这是因为他们在玩政治
-Did l show you a picture of Lucy Jean? -No, you didn't.
-我有否给你看过露珍的照片？ -没有
She's the one for me all right, that Lucy Jean.
她会是我的另一半
She's waiting for me too.
她也在等我
She's real pretty. You're a lucky guy, Gardner.
她很漂亮，你很幸福
You got a picture of your girl?
你有你女朋友的照片吗？
That leaves some unlucky girl back home, don't it?
那我们有一个被 留在家乡的可怜女孩，不是吗？
Tuck this in.
插进去
Shit-can this.
装进去
Don't need this. Turn around.
不需要这个，转身
Come on.
来吧
Tex! You got Junior and Taylor here on your position.
德斯！跟小尊和戴一队
Elias, don't mess with my pig.
奕礼，不要乱来
l ain't getting greased tonight. Keep this cheesedick off my ass.
我今晚不是去喝酒，别烦我
You got Taylor.
你有戴
Gardner, you're with me.
葛拿，你和我一组
ln case anything happens to you, you get lost or separated...
如果你迷路或和队友分开了
-...don't yell out, okay? -Okay.
-千万不要大叫，知道吗？ -知道
-Just sit tight and we'll get to you. -All right.
-不要到处走，我们会来找你 -好
Saddle up! Lock and load!
准备出发！小心谨慎！
Mom and Dad didn't want me to come here,
爸妈不想我来这里
They want me to be just like them,'
他们想我以他们为榜样
Respectable, hard-working, a little house, a family,
受人尊敬、工作勤劳、拥有家庭
They drove me crazy with their goddamn world, Grandma, You know Mom,
祖母，他们快把我逼疯 你知道妈妈的
Having always been sheltered and special...
我一向都备受保护…
...I want to be anonymous like everyone else,
我想像其他无名氏一样
Do my share for my country,
为国家效力
Live up to what Grandpa did in the first war, Dad in the second,
就像祖父在一次大战时一样 和爸爸在二次大战时一样
Well, here I am, Anonymous, all right,
我现在的确是无名氏了
With guys nobody really cares about,
和没人在乎的一班人一起
They come from the end of the line,
他们来自荒芜的地方
Small towns you never heard of,
你从没听过的小镇
Polaski, Tennessee, Brandon, Mississippi,
田纳西波兰斯基 密西西比布兰登
Pork Bend, Utah, Wampum, Pennsylvania,
犹他州波切本 宾夕凡尼亚的旺普
Two years high school's about it,
只念过两年高中
If they're lucky, a job waiting for them in a factory,
若他们幸运，会在工厂找到工作
Most of them got nothing,
他们大部分都一无所有
They're poor and unwanted...
他们穷苦而且不受欢迎
...yet they're fighting for our society and freedom,
但他们却为我们的 社会和自由而战
It's weird, They're the bottom of the barrel, and they know it,
真奇怪，他们自知是箩底橙
Maybe that's why they call themselves grunts,
所以他们自称平凡人
Because a grunt can take it, can take anything,
因为平凡人什么都能承受
They're the best I've ever seen, Grandma, The heart and soul,
他们是我见过最有真本性的人 祖母
Hey, Taylor?
戴
Hey, cheesedick, you're up.
新丁，轮到你
-What? -You're up.
-什么？ -轮到你
-Sure you can work the claymores? -l'm sure.
-你肯定懂得用杀伤地雷吗？ -我肯定
Flick the safety off and bang on it three times.
拉下安全栓和撞击三次
Three times. l got it.
三次，我知道了
Don't catch any Z's on me, or l'll sling your sorry ass! Hear me?
不要睡着，否则我不会放过你 知道吗？
Okay.
知道
Maybe I finally found it way down here in the mud,
或许我终于在泥泞里找到答案
Maybe from down here I can start up again,
或许我可以从这里重新来过
Be something I can be proud of without faking it, Be a fake human being,
也许我可以骄傲的做个 堂堂正正的虚假人
Maybe I can see something I don't yet see, learn something I don't yet know,
我或许能看见我还没看到的东西 学一些我还没学到的东西
I miss you, I miss you very much,
我想你，很想你
Tell Mom I miss her too, Chris,
告诉妈妈我想念她 基斯上
Junior.
小尊
-All right, motherfucker. -lt's your shift, man.
-好了，混蛋 -轮到你
Here, take this.
拿去
Blow the fucking claymore!
引爆地雷
Take the safety off! Damn it!
拉下安全栓
Get the safety off!
拉下安全栓，妈的
Feed me, Junior! Get over here and feed me!
救我，小尊 到这里来救我
-Jesus-fucking-Christ! -Easy, boy.
-我的天 -冷静下来
-Doc, Gardner's hit! -Right there!
-军医，葛拿被打中 -我快过来
Oh, shit. l'm hit!
我被击中
Doc, Taylor's hit! Taylor's hit!
军医，戴被击中
-Oh, shit. -Doc, doc!
-糟了 -军医
How bad is it?
伤势怎样？
He didn't blow his claymore!
他没有引爆地雷
Relax, man. lt's a scratch. Hold this on here.
放松，只是擦伤，按着
Don't lie. How bad is it?
不要骗我，伤势怎样？
He let them walk right up on us! He was asleep on his shift!
他让他们进入，他当值时睡着
No, l did not.
我没有
Big Harold, keep an eye on him.
海洛老大，留意着他
Don't let him go into shock.
不要让他休克
Shut up!
住口
Shut up and take the pain. Take the pain!
住口，忍住痛！忍住痛
Red rag, red rag, bravo six, I have NDPs at this time, Over,
总部，这是六队，我们被袭击 完毕
Hey, little guy, you're gonna be okay.
小伙子，你会没事的
Don't worry.
不用担心
Do you know if you're gonna die?
你是否知道你会不会死？
Do you feel it'll all be fine?
你感到一切都没事吗？
No morbid bullshit. You're about to get out of here.
胡说，你会离开这里
They're gonna give you three hot meals a day. White sheets.
他们会给你一日三餐，白床单
Pretty white nurses will give you blow jobs if you pay them.
漂亮的白人护士拿了你的钱 会给你性服务
-l heard about them white bitches. -Don't baby talk him.
-我听说过她 -不要哄他
The cocksucker fell asleep. He let them walk right up on us!
这个混蛋睡着了，他让他们进来
Just shut up, Junior.
小尊，住口
You relax. Okay, man?
放松，好吗？
lt's not so bad...
死亡不是…
...dying.
那么糟
How long?
多久？
Bird's on the way. Hang in there. You'll make it.
直升机快来了，撑着点 你会支持着的
Come on, Gardner, hang in there. You're gonna make it!
葛拿，支持着，撑着点 你会没事的
Come on. Don't quit.
别这样，不要放弃
Come on, Gardner, help me. Don't give up!
别这样，葛拿，不要放弃
You all take a good look at this lump of shit.
你们好好看看这个狗屎
Remember what it looks like.
你们要好好记住这样子
You fuck up in a firefight and l guarantee you a trip out of the bush...
如果你们行差踏错…
...in a body bag.
我保证你们不能活着离开
Out here, assholes, you keep your shit wired tight at all times.
在这里，混球，要提起精神
That goes for you, shit-for-brains.
你也是，猪脑
You don't sleep on no fucking ambush.
不能在埋伏时睡着
The next son of a bitch l catch copping Z's in the bush...
下次让我见到有人在埋伏时睡觉
...l'm personally gonna make him suffer.
我一定不会放过他
l shit you not.
我是很认真的
Tag him and bag him.
把他袋好搬走
l didn't fall asleep, sergeant.
我没有睡着
-lt was Junior. -Shut up, chickenshit.
-是小尊 -住口，鸟大便
You're in big trouble, boy.
你有麻烦了
Excuses are like assholes. Everybody's got one.
藉口像是屁眼 每个人都有一个
Knock it off!
别再胡闹
We got two men need attention here.
我们有两个队友需要照料
Police up your extra ammo and frags.
收拾好军火和手榴弹
Don't leave nothing for the dinks.
不要留任何东西给越南人
Carry Gardner.
背起葛拿
Man would be alive if he had a few more days to learn something.
若有多几天去学习，他不会死的
Hey, Taylor.
戴
What's in the breeze?
什么事？
Got light duty. Three days' worth.
三天轻松任务
No shit. Too bad we're in base camp anyway.
可惜我们在基地营
What you got? Beers?
你拿着什么？啤酒？
Stole some from the Top's supply. Shit, he's been stealing it from us.
从长官那里拿的 他偷我们的物资
What are you, back?
你回来了？
Yeah, it looks like it.
看来是了
Where'd you get the beers, boy?
你从哪里拿到的啤酒？
l found it.
我找到的
Found it? You're going on report, son, now.
找到？我会告发你
Both of you, come with me. l got a job for you.
你们跟我来，有工作给你们
Motherfucker!
混蛋
l'm too short for this shit, man.
我不适合做这个
They're always fucking with us.
他们总是在玩弄我们
No letup.
从没有停止过
Politics, man.
是政治
Fucking politics.
可恶的政治
That O'Neill's got his nose so far up Top's ass, he's gotta be Pinocchio.
奥尼拍长官的马屁 拍的都快成马屁精了
Thirty-nine and a wake-up.
39天之后
A pause for the cause and l'm a gone motherfucker.
我就能离开这里
-Back to the world. -l hear you.
-回到现实世界 -很好
l broke a hundred the other day.
我过了一百天
Ninety-two left to go. April 1 7th.
还有92天，4月17日
Home to California.
我便可以回加州了
l'll be sitting outside checking out the babes on the beach.
我会坐在海滩上看美女
The surfing's gonna be good.
冲浪一定会很好玩
March, man, in Tennessee.
三月在田纳西州
Sniff the pines. Sniff that pussy down by the river.
可以闻到松树的气味 可以在河边闻到女人的气味
Hot damn!
真棒
Hey, Taylor, how long you got left?
戴，你还有多少天？
-Three hundred and what? -Thirty-two.
-三百什么？ -三十二
Three hundred and thirty-two days.
332天
Sin loi, my boy.
傻小子
l can't even remember when l was 332, man.
我不记得那个日子了
You gotta count backwards or something, like you got 40 days in.
你要向前数，好像你已来了40天
Think positive, dude.
想的乐观些
How in the fuck did you get here anyway? You look educated.
你怎会来这里？你看来受过教育
-l volunteered for it. -You did what?
-我自愿来的 -什么？
l volunteered.
我自愿来的
l dropped out of college and told them l wanted infantry, combat, Vietnam.
我退出大学，想加入越战
You volunteered for this shit, man?
你自愿来的？
Can you believe that?
你能相信吗？
You is a crazy fucker, giving up college.
你放弃念大学实在太疯狂
lt didn't make much sense. l wasn't learning anything.
我在大学什么都学不到
Why should the poor kids go to war and the rich kids get away with it?
为什么穷人就要去打仗 有钱人就不用？
What we got here is a crusader.
他是个斗士
-Sounds like it. -Shit.
-看来是了 -可恶
You gotta be rich in the first place to think like that.
你一定是很富有才会那样想
Everybody knows...
大家都知道…
...the poor's always fucked over by the rich.
穷人总是被有钱人欺负
Always have, always will.
那是不能改变的事实
lf you be cool, l'll introduce you to some of the heads.
如果你上道 我会介绍一些大头给你认识
What are the heads?
什么样的大头？
Later, man.
晚一点吧
What's up, brother?
怎么了？
Your Highness has arrived. What's happening?
大人驾到，发生什么事？
l thought you was hanging ten in Cambodia.
我以为你在柬埔寨
Why are you in the underworld?
你为什么在这里？
This ain't Taylor. Taylor been shot. This is Chris. He been resurrected.
这个不是戴，戴中枪了 是基斯，他被救活了
You lame, Taylor?
戴，你跛了吗？
Are you lame or something?
你是跛的吗？
Go ahead, old man. Smoke it.
继续吧，抽一口吧
Your shit's in the wind, troop.
抽一口享受一下吧
Hey, man. What's happening?
你好吗？
lf you do that ''baa,'' you do it right.
不是那样叫的
You're weird, man.
你很古怪
You're a child. l don't waste time on you.
你是个孩子，我不会 在你身上浪费时间
-First time? -Yeah.
-第一次吗？ -是
Then the worm has definitely turned for you, man.
那么你一定会上瘾
Feel good?
感觉好吗？
Yeah, it feels good. l got no pain in my neck now.
队，感觉很好 我的脖子不痛了
Feeling good's good enough.
感觉很好已足够
Put your mouth on this.
放入口里
Where the hell is everybody, man?
大家在哪里？
They're getting high. Bunch of hopheads. They think they're special.
大家都正在享受，一群毒虫 他们觉得他们很特别
Listen to that. That's a bad jam.
你听，很糟的演奏
Redneck noise, dude. That's all it is.
烦透的噪音，就是那样
Make about as much sense as you do.
和你一样那么烦
All them chucks be rapping about how they losing their ho...
他们都在埋怨…
...saying how they ain't got no bread for beer.
埋怨自己没有钱
Fuck that honky shit! Gotta get me some Motown jams, dig it?
去他的！ 给我黑人音乐，开始吧？
What are you talking that shit for?
你干嘛那样说？
Junior, you ever smoke any shit?
小尊，你吸食过毒品吗？
That's right.
对
You trying to keep the black man down and string him out on that shit.
你们想用毒品荼毒黑人
But the time's coming when the black man will throw that yoke off.
但黑人很快就会推翻你们
Simple. Free your mind, your ass will follow.
很简单，释放你的心灵就行 你的身体就会跟随
Yeah, l can dig it, man. You smoke that shit and everything gets weird.
明白，你吸那东西 一切会变得离奇
You hear about gooks putting chemicals in the grass...
越南人在草丛散布化学毒药
...so we don't fight, so we become pacifists.
令我们不再打仗 变成反战者吧
But don't you worry, Bunny, you's a killer anyway.
不用担心，你怎样都是个杀手
But l still like a piece of pussy once in a while.
但我仍然喜欢女人
Nothing like a piece of pussy, except maybe the lndy 500.
除了赛车，没东西比得上女人
Only way you get pussy is if the bitch dies and wills it to you...
只有女人死了遗留她的身体 给你
...and then maybe.
你或许才会有
How's it going, Bunny?
宾尼，你好吗？
L.T.
中尉
Check it out.
你看
You like that?
你喜欢吗？
Terrific.
很棒
l'll send it home.
我会寄回家
Hey, Junior.
小尊
-Lieutenant. -Hello, sir.
-中尉 -你好
Rodriguez, that's quite a shrine you have.
罗志杰，你的寺庙很棒
Thank you, sir.
谢谢
-You need anything? -No, sir.
-你有什么需要吗？ -没有
Now, wait. This guy's three or four times my size.
这个人比我大三至四倍
He's in the O'Neill death grip.
他被奥尼勒着
He doesn't know whether to shit or go blind.
他不知道要害怕还是瞎了较好
-What do you say, L.T.? -How you doing, Red?
-中尉，你认为怎样？ -你好吗，里德？
Not good. This cocksucker has every card in the deck.
不好，他拿了所有的好牌
Full house.
呼鲁
You're doing all right.
你还不错
Yeah, and l ain't even cheating yet.
对，我还没开始作弊呢
-Lieutenant, some Kentucky windage? -Oh, thanks, Andy.
-中尉，要喝酒吗？ -谢谢
Play, lieutenant?
中尉，你想玩吗？
No. Wouldn't want to get raped by you guys.
不，我不想被你们强奸
Why's that, lieutenant? What are you saving up to be?
为什么？你留着为了谁？
Jewish?
犹太人？
l gotta run.
我要走了
l'll catch you men later. Enjoy yourselves tonight.
稍后再见，你们玩得高兴点
That is one sorry-ass motherfucker.
他真是一个混蛋
What do you say there, Bob? A guy like that make it? Yes or no?
你认为呢？彭？ 他能挨过这场仗吗？
l have to say that's precisely what l saw.
我也是那样想
Sometimes l just look at a guy, and l know he's not going to make it.
我只用看一看他就知道了
Just no fucking way.
他一定不行
New Year's Day, 1 968,
1968年，元旦
Just another day, Staying alive,
又是一天 仍然活着
Lots of movement near the Cambodian border, NVA regiments moving across,
敌军在柬埔寨边境 附近越过边界
A lot of little firefights, ambushes,
有很多交战和埋伏
We drop bombs, then we walk through the jungle like ghosts in a landscape,
我们投下炸弹后 像鬼魅般穿越丛林
Bunker.
地堡
Where?
哪里？
Bravo 2, Bravo 2-5, I've got beaucoup bunkers up here, Over,
B2，B25，这里有很多地堡 完毕
2-5, 2, Roger, Bunkers at point, Two actuals on the way, Over,
收到，有地堡 二队在前往途中，完毕
Bravo 6, Bravo 2, Be advised there is a bunker complex up front,
B6，B2，前面有地堡阵
We're on our way down, Over,
我们现在下去
See you next week.
下周见
Taylor, get your ass up on that flank, about 50 meters.
戴，去那边五十米以外
Washington, you cover this side.
华盛顿，你去这边
-Yes, sir. -Get off your ass, Harold.
-是 -海洛，快点
Shit.
可恶
Bummer!
真失望
Christ, look at that. The teapot's still boiling. They were just here!
天啊，看看这个 茶壶仍是烫的，他们刚离开
Man, this is spooky, Sander. Let's get out of here.
气氛很可怕，我们离开吧
Watch it, watch it!
小心
Look what we got, Sal.
你看我们找到什么
We got maps.
有地图
We got...
这里有…
-...S-2 stuff. -That's the gooks' stuff. Let's go!
-S2的东西 -那是越南军的，走吧
No, Sal, this is important. This is important.
不，这些东西很重要
Come on. Let's go.
我们走吧
Booby trap! Get down!
饵雷，伏下
Medic!
军医
Holy gee!
我的天
Goddamn it.
可恶
We got two men down, sir. There was an explosion.
刚才发生爆炸，两个士兵被炸伤
This-- We need help, sir. ASAP.
我们需要增援
Move your ass out of here! One round to get you all!
立即离开这里 一轮搏斗你们就完蛋
Rodriguez, move it! Junior, let's go!
罗德里，乔利亚，快点
Lieutenant.
中尉
Tell 6 we need engineers. This pos is full of traps.
告诉总部我们需要工程师 这里到处是陷阱
They're coming.
他们快来了
NVA were seen at a village half a klick down the river.
下面的村庄有北越军的踪影
Now, 6 says to get there ASAP.
六队说我们要立即赶去
Also, leave four of your men here and a medic.
留下四个手下和军医
-All right. -Move it out.
-好 -快点
Pull the flanks in! Let's move!
召集所有士兵，快点！
Hey, where's Manny?
曼尼在哪里？
Manny, where you at?
曼尼，你在哪里？
We had to reach the village before dark,
我们要在入黑前到达村庄
We left Elias and some men to keep looking and to wait for the engineers,
伊利亚等人继续找寻 和等候工程师
But it was King who found him...
但最后金找到他
...about 1 000 yards downriver, not far from the village,
他在下游一千码那里
It was the end of the mystery,
谜团被解开了
The motherfuckers.
混蛋
The village, which was maybe 1 000 years old, didn't know we were coming,
那个千年村的村民不知道我们会来
If they had, they would have run,
否则他们早就逃走
Barnes was at the eye of our rage and through him, our Captain Ahab...
巴恩是众矢之的 阿合上尉会经过他
...who would set things right again,
改善事情
That day, we loved him,
那一天我们都很敬爱他
There he goes, sarge.
他在那里
-Pick him up. -Yeah, you got it, sarge.
-把他捡起来 -好
Let's go.
快来
Get that stupid look off your face!
不要那样望着我
O'Neill, clear out these hooches.
奥尼尔，清除房子
Hey, piggy-piggy. Hey, pig.
小猪…
Bunny, you've got to bring the hooches down.
宾尼，你要烧掉房子
Spread out on the right. Watch your back. Let's go!
去右边，小心，出发！
What do you got here, huh?
这里有什么？
Get over there! Move it!
去那边，快！
Come on, let's go!
来吧，快点！
Let's go, Junior, bring them in.
乔利亚，集合他们
Get out of there, you fuckheads! Move!
出来，混球！行动！
Come on!
来吧
-Put them in the pigpen! -Get over here.
-把他们赶进猪栏去 -过来
Get back! Shut up!
回去！住口！
Give me your willie pete.
给我
Get back!
退后
Fire in the hole!
准备爆炸
Shut up!
住口
Get them out of here!
赶他们出来
Oh, fuck! We got one.
妈的！这里有一个
Get the fuck out of the hole!
赶他出来
Get out of there. Come on, motherfucker!
出来，混蛋
Be cool! Be cool! They're scared, man!
冷静下来，他们很害怕
Oh, they're scared, huh? What about me, man?
他们害怕？我又怎样？
l'm sick of this fucking shit! Come on, motherfucker, move!
我厌倦这样，快出来 混球，快！
Watch this fucker!
看看这混球
Who the fuck do they think we're fighting for?
他们认为我们为谁而战？
-You got one more! -Hey, hey!
-还有一个 -你…
Well, what have we here?
有什么发现？
They have one, two, three, four Mag 58 Czechoslovakian machine guns.
我们有一，二，三，四支机关枪 捷克制米克58机关枪
They got two, four....
他们有二、四…
Barnes, they got enough rice here to feed a whole fucking regiment.
他们有足够米粮供应一队军队
Sergeant Warren, you bring the honcho over here.
华伦，带村长来
Tubbs, get out of there! Junior, burn it!
特斯，出来，乔利亚，烧掉房子
What the fuck's the matter? l wasn't gonna hurt you!
怎么了？我不会伤害你
Look like l was gonna hurt you?
我看来想伤害你吗？
Why didn't you listen to me?! Why didn't you fucking listen to me?!
你为什么不听我说？ 你为什么不他妈的听我说？
Fucking stupid?! You stupid asshole!
你这个笨蛋！你这个王八！
Get the fuck up here! Come here, motherfucker!
他妈的过来！到这里！混球！
What are you smiling at?! Why the fuck didn't you listen to me?!
你在笑什么？ 你为什么不听我说？
Do them, man!
杀死他们
What are you smiling at?! You want something to smile at, huh?!
你在笑什么？ 想有点可笑的东西？
-You want something to smile at?! -That's right!
-想有点可笑的东西？ -对
-Dance, motherfucker! -Yeah!
-混蛋，跳舞吧 -对
Dance, one-legger!
跛子，跳舞吧
Dance! Dance!
跳舞…
Dance! One-legged motherfucker!
跳舞，跛子
Come on. Come on, let's go, man.
来吧
Fucking pussy, man! He's laughing at you!
他妈的！他在嘲笑你
That's the way the gook laughs.
越南人是那样笑的
Yeah, sure you are!
当然了
You're real sorry, ain't you?
你很后悔吧？
You're just crying your little hearts out about Sandy and Sal and Manny.
你为曼尼他们的死感到内疚吧？
Forget about it, Bunny, huh? Let's go.
宾尼，算了吧？我们走！
What do you say?
你说呢？
Holy shit! You see that fucking head come apart, man?
妈的！你看到他的头颅 是怎样爆开吗？
l never seen brains like that before, man.
我从来没见过那样的脑袋
l bet you the old bitch runs the whole fucking show.
我打赌一定是她指挥一切的
She probably cut Manny's throat. Probably cut my balls off if she could.
大概是她割开曼尼的喉咙 她一定也想把我的睾丸割掉
Bunny, we leave now, nobody saw a thing!
宾尼，离开吧，没有人看到什么
You understand, Taylor?
泰勒，你明白吗？
Come on, let's fucking do her! Let's do the whole fucking village!
杀死她吧，杀死整条村的人
There's scars on this gook honcho, sarge.
这个越南人头目脸上有些疤痕
Get out of here, Tubbs.
特斯，出来
Where did he get these wounds?
他从哪里弄到伤痕？
-Says he was hit in a bombing raid. -He's a dink for sure.
-他说他在轰炸中受伤 -他一定是北越的人
Ask him why these weapons are here.
问他这里为什么会有武器
They had no choice. The NVA killed the old honcho when he said no.
他们没有选择 北越杀了抗命的老头目
-He says all the rice is theirs. -Oh, bullshit, Lerner.
-他说那些米是属于他们 -莱纳，胡说
Who the hell was the gook we nailed on the riverbank?
我们在河边杀死的越军是谁？
He doesn't know. The NVA ain't been here in a couple of months.
他不知道，北越军几个月没来过
-Maybe he was a scout. -Yeah, sure. A scout.
-或许他是哨兵 -当然了
What about the rice and the weapons?! Who they for?!
那些米和武器是给谁的？
An NVC!
北越军
That cocksucker knows what l'm saying. Don't you?
他知道我在说什么吧？
Goddamn right he does.
他一定知道
He's lying!
他在说谎
Waste the fucker! Then see who talks.
杀死他，看谁会说真话
Look, he says he doesn't know anything.
他说他什么都不知道
He hates the NVA, but they come when they want and take over.
他讨厌北越但他们擅自来这里
What's the bitch saying?
她在说什么？
She's going on about why we killed the pigs...
她问我们为什么要杀死猪只
...they're farmers, they have to make a living....
他们是农夫，要养活自己
Shut up!
住口
Shut her the fuck up!
叫她住口
You tell him to start talking or l'll waste more of them.
你叫他快点说 否则我会杀死更多人
Tell him, Lerner!
莱纳，告诉他
Let us in on this, all right?
让我们大开杀戒
Let's go for it! Let's do the whole fucking village!
我们杀死整条村吧
Come on, sarge. What the fuck are we waiting for?
中士，我们还在等什么？
-Let's do them! -Out of my way!
-杀死他们 -走开
This is his daughter, right? Right?
这是他的女儿吧？
You lie! No, you lie! You VC!
你说谎！不，你说谎！ 你这个越共！
Barnes!
巴恩
What the fuck do you think you're doing?
你在他妈的做什么？
Stay out of this. lt ain't your show.
别管闲事，这和你无关
You ain't a firing squad, you piece of shit!
你不是火枪队，猪哥！
-Get him! -Come on, Barnes!
-打倒他 -巴恩，加油
Get him! Get him! Tear his fucking head off!
打倒他！… 打烂他的头！
Come on, Elias. Send him to hell!
伊利亚，杀死他
Goddamn it! Come on, break it up!
妈的！别这样！停手！
Break it up!
停手
Elias, chill.
伊利亚，冷静点
You're dead, Elias! l swear to fucking God, you're dead!
伊利亚，你死定了 我发誓，你死定了
You! You're gonna do time in LBJ!
你会坐牢的
This shit won't wash, you puke!
这件事不会就此罢休的，混蛋
Break it up! Break it up! Shut up!
停手！…住口！
Break it up! Listen up!
停手，留心听着
Captain says to torch this place, hear that?
上尉说烧掉这里，听到了吗？
Torch this place!
烧掉这里
Blow the weapons in place!
烧掉武器
Round up suspected VC and shake it up! We ain't got much light left!
集合他们，我们时间不多
Lieutenant, why the fuck didn't you do something?
中尉，你为什么不作出行动？
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
You know what the fuck l'm talking about.
你知道我在说什么
No, l don't. l don't know what the fuck you're talking about, Elias.
不，我不知道 我不知道你他妈的在说什么
Move it out! Let's go! You heard the lieutenant!
快点出发！快！听到命令了吧！
Taylor, let's go, for chrissake! Police up the weapons and let's go!
泰勒，走了，妈的！ 烧掉武器，然后离开
Come on, Harold.
哈洛，来吧
Fire in the hole!
准备爆炸
Hey, come on.
来吧
You fucker! Get out of here!
妈的！滚开
Get the fuck off! Don't do it! Don't do it!
滚开！…不要那样做
You fucker! What is this, huh?!
混蛋，这是什么一回事？
You a homosexual?
你是同志吗？
What's your problem? She's a fucking dink.
你怎么了？她是越南人
She's a fucking human being, man! Fuck you!
她是人类！去你的！
Total fucking cherry, Taylor!
泰勒，你这个可恶的新兵
Fucking animal! All of you! You're fucking animals!
妈的禽兽！你们全部都是禽兽！
Fucking lame fuck!
混蛋
You don't belong in the Nam. This ain't your place.
你不属于越南，这里不适合你
You don't fucking get it, do you?
你们一点都不明白吧？
You just don't fucking get it.
你们不明白
lt's okay.
没事的
Get out of there!
离开吧
Police up your dicks and let's go.
出发吧
-l didn't see anything, sir. -l did.
-我什么都看不见 -我看到
Sergeant Barnes reported the dink as NVA.
巴恩中士说那个是北越兵
My report will have Lieutenant Wolfe as being witness to the shooting.
我的报告中 沃夫上尉是目击证人
All right, Elias.
伊利亚，好
-Staff Sergeant Barnes. -Sir!
-巴恩中士 -是
l want a full report from you when we get back to the CP.
我们回到总部后我要详细报告
You got a diary. l have plenty of eyewitnesses, sir.
你有日志，我有很多目击证人
Not now, goddamn it! Not now!
不是现在
We'll get into this at the base camp.
我们回到总部才调查这件事
l can promise you, if l find out there was an illegal killing...
我保证如果发现非法杀戮…
...there will be a court-martial.
一定会有军事法庭
Right now, l need every man in the field, and you two will cease fire.
现在我要全军作战，你们别再吵
Staff Sergeant Barnes. Sergeant Elias. You hear me?
巴恩和伊利亚中士，听到吗？
-Yes, sir. -Yes, sir.
-是 -知道
We're going back into that NVA bunker tomorrow, this time from the east.
明天你们从东面再去那越共地堡
You people get some rest, and be back here at the CP at 1 900 for a briefing.
你们休息一下， 晚上七点钟回来开会
-Yes, sir. -Yes, sir.
-是 -是
Come on, man! You think these chucks give a fuck about you and me?
你认为他们会在乎我们吗？
lt could have been you, Harold, you got in Barnes' way.
哈洛，也许会是你阻碍了巴恩
And that Bunny?
那个宾尼呢？
That motherfucker's crazy.
他是疯的
l mean, he scares me.
他令我不寒而栗
He just scares me.
他很可怕
You bloods are getting too hung up on this shit.
你已经受牵连
These gooks are a lot smarter than you think.
这些越南人比你想像中聪明
You know, Barnes knows his shit, man.
巴恩知道他在做什么
They was NVA, every last of them.
他们是北越兵
He got us this far. He'll get us the rest of the way.
他带领我们走到这里了 他会带领我们走完这场战争
l don't know, Holmes.
我不知道
A Christian don't go around a village, cutting off heads and shit.
基督教徒不会到处杀人
This shit is really getting out of hand, blowing out of control.
情况失去控制了，完全失控了
Seems to me that you don't seem to know the difference...
看来你不知道怎样分别…
...the way you always shoot up that shit.
事情的轻重
l don't know, brothers...
我不知道…
...but l'm hurting real bad inside.
但我内心大受伤害
Don't worry, sarge. Elias won't be able to prove a thing.
别担心，伊利亚不能证明什么
He's a troublemaker.
他是个麻烦制造者
Elias is a water walker. Like them politicians in Washington...
伊利亚像华盛顿的政客…
...trying to fight this war with one hand tied around their balls.
想独力打这场仗
Ain't no need or time for a courtroom out here.
这里没有时间进行审讯
-Sarge. -Thanks, Bun.
-中士 -谢谢你
How did it go there, Bob?
情况怎样？
Yeah, thataway, sarge! Fucking Elias, man.
那个可恶的伊利亚
He's a fucking rat, that's what he is.
他是个卑鄙小人
He'll get everybody in this platoon in deep shit.
他会连累这个连的所有人
Somebody ought to frag his ass.
有人要教训他
So, what do you think? Gonna be an investigation or what?
你认为呢？ 会有调查吗？
Bob?
鲍布？
O'Neill, you worry too much. Sarge will take care of him.
你太担心了，中士会解决他
lt's a beautiful night.
今晚天色很美
Yeah, l love this place at night.
我喜欢这里的夜晚
The stars....
繁星…
There's no right or wrong in them. They're just there.
它们没有对与错 它们就是在那里
That's a nice way of putting it.
你的比喻很好
Barnes has it in for you, huh?
巴恩憎恨你吧？
Barnes believes in what he's doing.
巴恩相信他所做的一切
And you? Do you believe?
你呢？你相信吗？
ln '65? Yeah.
1965年时吗？我会相信
Now?
现在呢？
No.
不相信
What happened today is just the beginning.
今天所发生的事只是开始
We're gonna lose this war.
我们会输掉这场仗
Come on.
不会吧
You really think so? Us?
你真的认为我们会输？
We've been kicking other people's asses for so long...
我们欺负别人太久了
...l figure it's time we got ours kicked.
现在轮到我们被打击
Day by day, I struggle to maintain...
我每天都在挣扎
...not only my strength, but my sanity,
我努力维持体力和意志
It's all a blur,
一切都很模糊
I have no energy to write,
我没有气力写信
I don't know what's right or wrong anymore,
我不能分辨对与错
The morale of the men is low, A civil war in the platoon,
我们的士气低落，出现内讧
Half the men with Elias, half with Barnes,
一半支持伊利亚，一半支持巴恩
There's a lot of suspicion and hate,
有很多猜忌和憎恨
I can't believe we're fighting each other instead of them,
我们竟然在自伤残杀
Counting days and the six inches in front of my face, Not much else,
数着日子和留意着周遭，没别的
Hope things are well, Grandma,
祖母，希望你一切安好
Tell Mom and Dad I--
告诉妈妈和爸爸…
Well, just tell them, Chris,
你知道告诉他们什么的 柯里斯上
Hey, big boy. l know you thought you had that laundry gig all laid out.
我知道你以为会被派去洗衣服
Hell, l gotta paint myself white just to get one of those jobs.
我要把自己涂白 才能得到那些工作
Got my request in for a circumcision. l'm getting my big ass out of here.
我递了申请去割包皮，我要离开
What are you gonna do, become a rabbi?
你会成为犹太教教士吗？
Leech.
水蛭
All right! Move it out!
继续走
Don't drink that, asshole. You're gonna get malaria.
不要喝，你会得到痢疾
Yeah, l hope so.
我希望会
Let's go.
去吧
Doc! Up here! Lerner's hit!
军医，莱纳被击中
Sergeant, Warren's hit!
中士，华伦被击中
-What's going on? -They got RPGs, man!
-发生什么事？ -他们有火箭榴弹
lt's an ambush! They were just waiting for us here!
他们已在这里埋伏了很久
-Who's on point? -Lerner and Warren.
-谁负责防守？ -莱纳和华伦
Where are you going?!
你去哪里？
Goddamn it, you assholes! Get some firepower up there!
天啊！混球！派火力上前
Right!
对
Watch out! Rockets!
小心，火箭
Where the fuck is Lerner?
莱纳在哪里？
He's over there! By the log!
他在木头那边
Fire mission. Grid: 6-4-9-4-0-2.
开火坐标649602
Direction: 6-1 -0--
方向610
Adjust fire. Over.
调整发射，完毕！
Lieutenant, they'll get in tight under the arty!
中尉，他们会步步进逼
l saw a cut. Let me take some men and roll up that flank.
我看到缺口，让我带人去那边
Get Barnes! Elias, we got four down. What do you want me to do?
叫巴恩去，我们已有四个人受伤 你要我怎么办？
Where the fuck is Red Platoon?! Tell those assholes to get up here!
红连在哪里？叫那些混蛋赶来
Elias, what are you doing back here?
伊利亚，你在这里做什么？
There's holes back here, 3rd Platoon's coming up here, we're here!
第三连在这里，我们在这里
Dinks get in these holes, we'll be in a crossfire.
若越军进入这些洞我们就要交锋
-We'll shoot each other. -Sounds far-out to me.
-我们会互相开火 -听来很不寻常
l've seen it happen. la Drang in '66.
我在1966年的战役里见过
They cut us to pieces. l need three men.
他们会击溃我们，我需要三个人
You got them! Take off!
好，去吧
You keep pouring off that cover fire.
继续掩护我们
l don't want to be stuck out there with my ass hanging in the breeze.
我不想在外面孤军作战
You don't tell me how to run my war, Elias.
伊利亚，不要教我怎样打仗
You go crying to fucking brigade on your own time.
你去吆喝你的手下好了
Out here you belong to me! Now, move!
在这里你属于我，快行动！
You're an asshole, Barnes.
巴恩，你是个混蛋
Get that asshole O'Neill up here!
叫奥尼尔上前来
Holy fuck,
可恶
Stay down!
伏下
Ammo! Ammo!
子弹…
Sarge! Short round!
中士，子弹不够
Fucking idiot!
混蛋
Get it out!
拿出来
Medic!
军医
Satchel charge!
有地雷
-Doc, help me out. -All right, down.
-军医，过来帮我 -好
Jesus.
天
-You okay? -Don't leave me, man.
-你没事吧？ -不要留下我
-You all right? -Don't leave me, man.
-你会没事的 -不要留下我
Gator? Gator, you'll be okay.
你会没事的
Let him go, man.
放开他
-Drop your rucks. -Taylor, you're coming with us.
-别吵 -泰勒，你跟我们来
Please don't go.
求你不要走
You're gonna be okay.
你会没事的
Come on.
来吧
Doc, take care of him, man.
军医，照顾他
Redleg, Redleg. Ripper Bravo 2 actual.
炮手，B2实际射程
Adjustment follows: Bridge....
调整方位，B…
You ignorant asshole!
你这个自大混蛋
What the fuck coordinates are you giving?
你给他们什么座标？
You wasted a lot of people up there with your fucked-up fire mission!
你的座标已经令很多人受伤
Do you know that?
你知道吗？
Do you know that? Ah, shit!
你知道吗？妈的！
Redleg! Redleg! Ripper Bravo 2.
炮手，这是B2
Check your fire! Check your fire!
停火…
They're coming.
他们来了
Stagger yourself across this line. Shoot anything that moves.
坚守这里 枪杀任何走动着的东西
They'll be coming from over there.
他们会从那里过来
Any one of them gets through, we are truly fucked.
只要被他们攻破，我们便死定了
Where the hell are you going?
你去哪里？
Down by the river about 1 00 meters...
到下游大约一百米处…
...in case they try to flank us.
以防他们准备从外围进攻
3rd Platoon is coming behind us. Watch for them.
第三连正在后面赶来
Hey. Can l go with you?
我可以和你一起去吗？
No. l move faster alone.
不，我单独行事较敏捷
Let's let arty do a bit of the work.
让炮兵队来处理
Tell everyone to pull back to the church...
叫所有人去教堂…
...and link up with 3rd Platoon. You got that?
和第三连会合，知道吗？
What about Elias? lf we pull back, he'll be cut off.
伊利亚怎样？他会孤立无援
You just haul ass too, lieutenant.
中尉，你也快去
l'll get him.
我去找他
Come on,
去吧
-l got two of them fuckers, man. -l got one.
-我击中两个 -我击中一个
Ho Chi Minh sucks dead dick!
打倒胡志明
Crawford!
克罗福
Oh, man. Oh, man.
糟了
Kiss my ass. Man, l never thought l'd get hit.
妈的，我从没想过会被击中的
A lung, babe. You got two of them fuckers.
你击中两个混蛋
Where's Elias? A bunch of gooks came through here.
伊利亚在哪里？一班越兵刚经过
-We got three of them fuckers. -Hey!
-我们击中三个 -对
The arty shifted. We're pulling back.
炮兵队调动了 我们要撤退
Get your wounded man and get the fuck back to church.
扶伤者去教堂
-Elias is still out there. -l'll get him.
-伊利亚在外面 -我会去找他
Get Crawford in now before l Article 1 5 both your asses. Move.
在我送你去军法审判之前 快扶克罗福进去，快
Move it!
快点
Almost there, brother. Come on.
快到达了，快
Medic, where the fuck are you?
军医，你在哪里？
lt's gonna be all right in a minute.
你很快会没事
Taylor, where are you going?
泰勒，你去哪里？
Elias is dead.
伊利亚死了
Fall back with the platoon.
和他们一起撤退
Get going.
快点
He's dead?
他死了？
Yeah, he's back there about 1 00 meters.
对，他在一百米外
You saw him? Where?
你看到他吗？哪里？
He's dead! There's gooks all over the goddamn place! Get moving!
他死了，到处都是越军，快走
Let's go! Come on, move it!
来吧
Let's go! Move it! Okay, let's go!
走吧！快！快走！
You okay, Harold? You're on the next one! You're okay, bud!
哈洛，你没事吧？下一个轮到你
Oh, fuck!
糟了
They've got Elias!
他们抓到伊利亚
What?
什么？
Back down! Back down there!
退后…
Snake 1-9, Fly 4, There's still one of the men down there,
蛇1-9队、飞行4 下面仍然有一个士兵
Hold your arms, Guns, hold off,
停火…
He killed him.
他杀死他
l know he did. l saw his eyes when he came in.
我知道是他，我看到他的眼神
How do you know the dinks didn't get him? You got no proof.
你怎知不是越兵？你没有证据
Proof's in the eyes. When you know, you know.
证据就在他的眼神，我看得出
You saw. l know what you were thinking.
你也看见，我知道你在想什么
l say we frag him tonight.
我们今天解决他
l go with that. An eye for an eye.
我赞成，以牙还牙
l say let military justice do the job on him.
让军事法庭处理吧
Come on, fuck the military justice! Are you joking me?
去他的军事法庭！ 你在说笑吗？
Whose story you think they'll believe? O'Neill's? Bunny's? Bullshit!
他们会相信谁？奥尼尔？宾尼？ 全是胡说！
You try that, Barnes will shove it back up your ass, with a candle on it.
巴恩不会放过你的
What do you suggest we do?
你认为我们应怎做？
Watch your own asses. Barnes will be coming down on all of them.
你们小心， 巴恩会一个个的解决他们
You gonna forget about Elias? All the good times we had here?
你们忘记和伊利亚的 美好日子吗？
Shit, you trying to cure the headache by cutting off the head.
你想把头砍下来治头痛？
Elias didn't ask you to fight his battles for him.
伊利亚没有叫你为他打仗
And if there's a heaven, and God, l hope there is...
如果真的有天堂，天啊 我希望真的有
...he's sitting up there drunk as a fucking monkey and smoking shit...
他会在上面喝到大醉
...because he left his pains down here.
因为他把痛苦留在这里
You're wrong! Anyway you cut it, Barnes is a murderer!
你错了，总之巴恩是杀人凶手
-Right on. -Taylor...
-对 -泰勒…
...when you first came in here, you told me how you admired the bastard.
你当初入伍时说很欣赏巴恩
-l was wrong. -You've never been right about nothing!
-我错了 -你做任何事都是错的
Dig this, you assholes, and dig it good.
你们这班混蛋，留心听着
Barnes been shot seven times, and he ain't dead.
巴恩中枪七次都没有死去
Does that mean anything to you?
那对你有意思吗？
Barnes ain't meant to die.
巴恩是不会死的
The only thing that can kill Barnes is Barnes.
唯一能杀死他的是他自己
Talking about killing?
你们在谈死亡吗？
You all experts?
你们是专家吗？
You all know about killing?
你们都知道杀戮吗？
Well, l'd like to hear about it, potheads.
我想听听，猪头
You smoke this shit to escape from reality?
你们抽这个来逃避现实？
Me, l don't need this shit.
我不需要这个
l am reality.
我就是现实
There's the way it ought to be, and there's the way it is.
现实应该是这样 而现实就是这样
Elias was full of shit.
伊利亚满口一派胡言
Elias was a crusader.
伊利亚是个斗士
Now, l got no fight with any man who does what he's told.
我不会跟听从命令的人作对
But when he don't...
但当他不听命时…
...the machine breaks down.
运作便会崩溃
And when the machine breaks down, we break down.
运作崩溃时 我们就会崩溃
l ain't going to allow that.
我不会许容那样的事
From any of you.
你们任何一个都不能
Not one.
一个都不可以
You all love Elias.
你们都爱伊利亚
You want to kick ass.
你们想为他报仇
Well, here l am. All by my lonesome.
我独个儿在这里
And ain't nobody gonna know.
没有人会知道
Six of you boys against me.
你们六个对我一个
Kill me.
杀我吧
l shit on all of you.
我卑视你们
You motherfucker!
混蛋
Come on, man.
打吧
Get him, Chris.
柯里斯，打他
Easy, Barnes. Don't do it, man!
巴恩，不要下手
You'll go dinky dau in LBJ, man.
你要坐牢的
Ten years for killing an enlisted man. Ten years.
杀军人要坐十年牢，十年
Climb the fucking walls, man.
你想想吧
Don't do it.
不要下手
Death?
死亡？
What do you all know about death?
你们对死亡有什么认识？
They sent us baCk into the valley the next day...
我们翌日被派回到山谷里
...about 2000 meters from Cambodia into a battalion perimeter,
进入离柬埔寨约二千米的战区
It felt like we were returning to the sCene of a Crime,
我们好像回到案发现场
Alpha Company had been hit hard the day before by a sizable forCe,
A连在前一天被重击
Charlie Company had been probed that night,
C连在那一天被袭击
There were other battalions in the valley...
山谷里有其他战事…
...but we knew we were the bait to lure them out,
但我们是引他们出来的饵
Somewhere out there was the entire 1 4 1 st NVA regiment,
141北越军就在下面某处
Caught them trying to pull some shit on Charlie Company last night.
他们昨晚想袭击C连
They found maps on them, man.
他们发现地图
Got a friend at Battalion, says they had every foxhole here fixed on.
听说每个散兵坑都有地雷
Distances, tree lines, our claymores, everything.
知道我方的距离、林木线和地雷
This is bad, man.
情况不妙
-l got bad vibes here. -l also heard we're in Cambodia now.
-我有不祥之兆 -听说我们身在柬埔寨
Cambodia? Man, you're kidding me.
柬埔寨？你在开玩笑
You wanted to see me, sir?
你想见我？
Yeah, Ramucci. Looks like you got Elias' squad now.
拉姆治，伊利亚小组归你
Squad? l didn't know we were still referring to this platoon as squads.
小组？我不知道我的连叫小组
l want you to take those two holes, right there and there.
我要你去那两个坑
Tie it off with Barnes up here and King down there.
跟在上面的巴恩 和在下面的金联络
Begging your pardon, sir...
长官，对不起…
...my two holes are so far apart, a regiment could run between them.
那两个坑距离太远 一个连队可以从中通过
l have five live bodies left.
我只有五个军人活着
l don't want to hear your problems. You'll get new men any day.
我不想听你的问题，新兵很快到
Make do like everybody else.
你要和别人一样作战
-l didn't ask for this. -l don't want to hear it.
-我没有要求这个 -我不想再听
-You don't want to hear it? -That's right.
-你不想再听？ -对
Because, to tell you the truth, l don't give a shit.
因为老实说我毫不在乎
l just don't give a flying fuck anymore.
我不再在乎
l'm glad l ain't going with them.
我很高兴我不用和他们一起去
Somewhere out there is the beast and he hungry tonight.
外面有一头饥饿的野兽
What a fucking bummer.
真失败
Ten days and a wake-up, and l'm still dealing with this shit.
只剩十天了，我仍要面对这一切
What's the matter with you?
你怎么了？
Why ain't you writing nobody?
你为什么不写信？
What about your folks?
你的父母呢？
That grandma you told me about?
你向我提起的祖母怎样？
Girl?
女朋友？
You got parents, don't you?
你有父母吧？
There must be somebody.
一定有些亲密的人
No, there's nobody.
没有
You been smoking too much of this shit.
你抽太多了
Gotta control that. Bring a man down.
你要控制一下 令人颓丧
l remember when you first come out here to the bush, you's green as--
我记得你初来时什么都不懂
You ever get caught in a mistake you just can't get out of?
你可曾被无法 摆脱的错误缠绕着？
There's a way out of anything.
总有方法解决的
Just keep your pecker hard and your powder dry...
只要你振作精神
...and the worm will turn.
一定有方法的
How many days you short?
你还有多少天？
lt's not just me. lt's how the whole thing works.
不只是我，而是整个事情
People like Elias get wasted.
像伊利亚般的人要牺牲
People like Barnes go on making up all the rules any way they want.
巴恩那种人却能继续为所欲为
So, what do we do? Sit in the middle and suck on it.
我们只能逆来顺受吗？
We just don't add up to dry shit.
我们不用理会那些事情
Whoever said we did? All you got to do is make it out of here...
谁说你需要的？ 你只需要活着离开这里
...and it's all gravy. Every day, the rest of your life. Gravy.
然后每天快乐地生活
Oh, shit. Superlifer.
你是理想主义者
Collect up your shit. Your orders just come through.
收拾你的行装 你的命令刚下达
Man, don't fuck with me.
不要骗我
Oh, what do you need, a written invitation?
你要邀请信吗？
Cocksucker! Oh, wow! The lifers done made a mistake!
天啊！他们做错事
They cut me some slack!
他们竟然饶我一命
You got 1 0 minutes to make the last fucking chopper out of here.
你有十分钟时间赶去搭直升机
Because if you're not on it...
因为如果你不上机…
...l'm gonna be.
我便会去
Taylor, Francis is coming up.
泰勒，法兰西准备好了
That's great, King, l'm happy for you. Take it on home for me.
太好了，金，我为你 感到高兴，回家吧！
You got my address. You know where to reach me anytime.
你有我的地址 你知道怎么联络我
l gotta di di, Don't want to miss that chopper.
我要走了，我不想错过直升机
-You okay? -Yeah, l'm okay.
-你没事吧？ -我没事
Remember, take it easy.
记住放松点
Don't think too much. Don't you be no fool.
不要想太多 别做傻瓜
Remember, ain't no such thing as a coward out here.
记住这里没有人是懦夫
My man.
我的朋友
l'll walk you out, man.
我送你出去
Take it easy, King.
金，保重
-l'll take it any way l can get it. -l hear you. Later.
-我会 -再见
l'm pretty fucked up, sarge. Don't touch it!
很痛，中士，不要碰它
l gotta get on the chopper, man.
我一定要上直升机
-So, what's the problem? -Says he can't walk.
-有什么问题？ -他说不能走路
Shit.
可恶
Martin...
马丁…
...get your boots on.
穿上靴子
And the next time l catch you spraying skeeter repellent on your feet...
下次给我见到你喷防蚊水…
...l'll court-martial your nigger ass.
我会送你上军事法庭
Then court-martial me, motherfucker!
送我去吧
Bust my ass! Send me to fucking Long Binh!
逮捕我啊！送我去坐牢吧
Do your fucking worst!
下手吧
You white folks got your last klick out of Junior!
你们白人欺负我
O'Neill, get me that centipede.
奥尼尔，把蜈蚣拿来
-Sarge? -Yeah.
-中士？ -是
That long, hairy, red and black bastard l found in the ammo crate.
我找到那毛茸茸、红黑色的虫
l'm gonna put it in this boy's crotch.
我会把它放进他的伤口
l remember now.
我记得了
Hold up, man!
等一下
You just hold up and wait, okay?
等一下好吗？
Fuck it, l'll walk! l'll fucking walk!
我会走路了
Fucking pussy! Sarge, l gotta have him in my hole?
我要和他同一个坑？
Yeah.
对
Bob, l'd like to speak to you a minute.
我可以和你谈谈吗？
l can't take it no more.
我不能再忍受了
Yeah, what is it?
什么事？
Bob, l got Elias' R and R. lt's coming up in three days.
我有伊利亚的假期 有三天
l was thinking about going to Hawaii and see Patsy.
我想回去夏威夷见柏丝
l never asked you for a thing over here.
我从没向你要求过任何事
Well, to be honest with you...
坦白说…
...l was hoping you'd put me on a chopper with King. What do you say?
我想和金一起坐直升机回去 你觉得呢？
l can't do that for you.
我不能让你那样做
You know we need every swinging dick in the field.
你知道这里很需要人手
You can talk to me, for chrissake! l'm just asking for three days.
你可以跟我说 我只是请三天假
l am talking to you, Red. And l'm telling you no.
我告诉你不可以
Get back in your foxhole.
回到散兵坑
Bob, l've got a bad feeling on this one, all right?
我有不祥之兆，知道吗？
l mean l've got a bad feeling.
我今次有不祥之兆
l don't think l'm gonna make it out of here.
我觉得我不能活着离开这里
You understand what l'm saying?
你明白吗？
Everybody gotta die sometime, Red.
每个人都会死的
Oh, shit!
可恶
Goodbye, motherfuckers!
混蛋们，再见
Where's that fucking ambush?
埋伏在哪里？
They ain't even waiting till later. lt's fucking coming now, man.
他们不会等，他们现在就来了
Right fucking now.
现在就来了
You know, Junior? Some of the things we done, man...
乔利亚，我们所做的一切
...l don't feel like we done something wrong.
我不觉得我们在做错事
But sometimes, man...
但有时…
...l get this bad feeling.
我有不祥的感觉
l told the padre the truth. l like it here.
我坦然对随军牧师说我喜欢这里
You get to do what you want, nobody fucks with you.
你可以为所欲为，没有人理会你
The only worry you got is dying.
你只用担心死亡
And if that happens, you won't know about it...
反正死的时候你不会知道
...so, what the fuck, man?
那么担心什么？
Shit. l got to be in this hole with you, man?
我要和你同一个坑？
l just know l shouldn't have come.
我早知道我不应该来
Don't you worry, Junior. You're hanging with Audie Murphy here.
不用担心，你和爱迪墨菲在一起
Bravo 3, Bravo 6. Send me a grid, send me a grid. Over.
B3、B6，给我座标… 完毕
I Can't, sir, We're pinned down, They're in the trees,
我不能，我们被困住了 他们在树丛里
Okay, 3 Alpha, now calm down, son. l'll get you a fire mission ASAP.
好，3A，冷静下来 我会立即派人去轰炸
-Smoke will be first. -Lieutenant and radioman are dead,
-先会发放烟雾 -中尉和电讯兵已经死了
I Can't find the map,
我找不到地图
They're all around us, Hundreds of them, I Can hear them talking gook,
他们分布在四周，好几百个 我听到他们说越南话
3 Alpha, spot that smoke and tell me where to shift.
3A，看着烟雾 告诉我要转向哪里
Just calm down. Hang in there. We'll get you out.
冷静下来，撑着点 我们会救你
Where did the rounds hit? Over.
哪里被袭？完毕
3 Alpha 6, how about those rounds? Can you adjust fire? Over.
3A6，你可以调整 开火位置吗？完毕？
3 Alpha 6, if you can't talk, just key your handset twice. Over.
3A6，如果你不能说话 按键两次，完毕
Shit.
糟了
Trip flare, Rodriguez's hole.
罗德里的坑被击中
RPG.
火箭榴弹
-Taylor. Francis. -Over here, man!
-泰勒、法兰西 -这里
What's going on? Rodriguez's hole just got nailed.
发生什么事？罗德里的坑被炸
Here it is. We got gooks in the fucking perimeter.
来了，附近满布越南兵
Shit. That's it!
完了…
They got through Alpha Company. Anything that don't identify itself...
他们打败了A连
...fucking blow it away.
向任何不明物体开枪
Fuck. Air strikes coming in. They'll be laying snake and nape.
妈的，空军正在赶来 他们会拼命投弹的
Don't get out of your fucking holes. Stay right here.
不要离开散兵坑
Fuck.
糟了
They're probing us.
他们在侦察我们
They'll go up and down, trying to get through.
他们不惜一切地攻入
All right, stay here. Stay cool. l'll be right back.
留在这里，冷静点 我很快回来
Foxtrot, Foxtrot, ECho, Whiskey, Over,
F队，回音，威士忌 完毕
Who is it?
是谁？
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
不要开枪
lt's the ambush. Over here, man, hurry!
是埋伏，这边
-Shit. -Water!
-糟了 -水
They're all over the place! Hundreds of them! Moving this way.
他们到处都是，正走向这里
They wiped us out! We didn't have a chance.
他们击溃我们 我们没有还击机会
-Where's the CP? -Back there.
-总部在哪里？ -后面
Get out of here! They're on my ass! They ain't stopping for shit!
快离开，他们不会停止的
Hey, Taylor, let's di di,
泰勒，我们走吧
You go.
你走
There.
那边
No, hold it. Hold it.
停火…
Out of the hole! Fast!
快离开
Get out of the foxhole! They're gonna blow it!
快立刻壕沟 他们想炸掉兵坑
Let's go! Let's go!
走吧…
Fuck's sake. Move your fucking ass! They're gonna blow--
快点走，快！他们要炸掉…
Fuck me.
很可怕
Wait!
等一下
Die, you motherfuckers!
混蛋，死吧
lt's fucking beautiful!
很漂亮
What are you doing? Where are you going?
你在做什么？你去哪里？
Come on, motherfuckers!
来吧
You can do better than that!
你们能做得更好
They just keep coming, man! Fuck this shit.
他们不断进攻
Get back here, you gutless shit!
回来，你这个懦夫
Get me Bravo ASAP.
给我B连
Charlie Company reports hand-to-hand, three holes are down. They need help.
C连报告三个坑失守，需要增援
Okay, get two squads from Alpha down there right away. Go, go!
立即派A连的两个小组前去 快！
Where's that goddamn air strike?
空袭在哪里？
Hey, you two! Where the fuck are you going?
你们去哪里？
Can't you get anybody?
联络不到任何人吗？
Negative contact. Can't raise Barnes, 2 Bravo, 2 Charlie, nothing!
不行，联络不到巴恩他们
-Get me 6! -Bravo 6!
-给我联络总部 -总部
-Parker's hit! -Get him in!
-柏加被击中 -拉他进来
They're coming through our line!
他们正在攻入
-Where's Barnes?! -He's dead! They're all dead!
-巴恩在哪里？ -他死了，他们全都死了
Six, L.T.!
六队，中尉
Captain, we've been overrun. We're pulling back. Over.
中尉，我们被袭击，我们会撤退
Goddamn it! Where will you pull back to? They're all over the perimeter!
妈的！撤退到哪里？ 到处都是他们
Now you be advised! You will hold in place and you will fight!
你听着，你们要坚守作战
That means you, lieutenant. Bravo 6 out.
中尉，即是指你，六队通话完毕
We got zips in the wire down here.
这里被袭
Roger that, Bravo 6, Can't run it any Closer,
收到，B6，但我们不能再接近了
We're paCking snake and nape but we're bingo on fuel,
我们准备投弹，我们燃料充足
For the record, it's my call! Dump all you've got on my pos.
这是我的决定，投下所有炸弹
l say again, expend all remaining in my perimeter.
我再说投下所有炸弹
lt's a lovely fucking war. Bravo 6 out.
这是一场很棒的战争 B6通话完毕
Roger your last, Bravo 6, We Copy it's your Call,
收到，这是你的决定
Get them in their holes, Hang tough, Bravo 6,
叫他们留守散兵坑 你们支持着
We are Coming CoCked for treetops,
我们会从树顶投下炸弹
Barnes!
巴恩
No!
不要
Get me a medic.
给我找军医
Go on, boy!
快去
Do it.
下手吧
Look out, we got live gooks at 3:00.
小心，三点钟位置还有越兵活着
Come on, Elmo! Move your flea-bitten ass!
快点
You okay? You all right?
你没事吧？
Can you walk?
你能走动吗？
Hey, doc! We need a medic up here!
这里需要军医
-Come on, Elmo. -Doc, we got wounded here!
-来吧 -这里有伤兵
That must have been some fucking fight.
战争一定是很激烈
You alone here, man?
只有你一个吗？
Yeah.
是
Bunch of fucking faggots. They all left me.
那些混球 他们留下我
1 22 wounded and still counting.
122个受伤，仍在点算中
Estimate 500...
估计有五百个伤者…
...Victor Charlie K.l.A. 22 and still counting. Over.
敌军22人阵亡，仍在点算中 完毕
Taylor! That you?
泰勒，是你吗？
Hey, Francis.
法兰西
-Hey, man, how you doing? -l'm okay. How you doing?
-你好吗？ -我还好，你好吗？
Fine, man. Just fine.
我很好
Hey, dig it, we two-timers. We're gonna get out of here, boy.
我们受过两次伤可以离开这里
l'm gonna see you in the hospital. We gonna get high, high. Yes, sir.
在医院再见
-How you doing? -l'm just fine, sir.
-你好吗？ -我没事
Good, because you got 2nd Platoon.
好，因为第二连由你指挥
Yes, sir.
是
-Ready? -You bet.
-准备好吗？ -准备好
I think now, looking baCk...
现在回想一切…
...we did not fight the enemy, we fought ourselves...
我们不是对抗敌人，而是自己
...and the enemy was in us,
敌人就在我们心中
The war is over for me now...
战争对我来说现在已经完结
...but it will always be there the rest of my days,
但它永远会存留在我的心中里
As I'm sure Elias will be...
伊利亚会和…
...fighting with Barnes for, what Rhah Called, possession of my soul,
巴恩为了，像罗德所说的 “灵魂的掌控”继续作战
There are times sinCe...
我有时会觉得…
...I have felt like the Child born of those two fathers,
我是那两个父亲的儿子
But be that as it may...
但无论如何…
...those of us who did make it have an obligation to build again,
我们有责任重建社会…
To teaCh to others what we know...
教导别人我们认识的一切…
...and to try with what's left of our lives...
我们利用剩下的一生…
...to find a goodness and meaning to this life,
尝试找寻生命的意义